<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Readium.js]]></title>
  <link href="http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-31T10:11:14-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Justin Hume]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Readium.js]]></title>
    <link href="http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/blog/2013/05/29/welcome-to-readium-js/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-29T02:11:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/blog/2013/05/29/welcome-to-readium-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the new Readium.js reference site and blog!</p>

<h2>Easy, open, web</h2>

<p>Readium.js is a BSD licensed open-source project that makes it simple to build EPUB 3 web applications, or to embed EPUB 3 publications in web applications.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It&#8217;s designed to be web-centric, light-weight and simple to use. The Readium.js library provides a set of javascript modules and APIs that can be easily added to any web project.</p>

<h3>The project &amp; contributors</h3>

<p>Readium.js is a project under the auspices of the <a href="">International Digital Publishing Forum</a> (IDPF), developed and maintained by <a href="">Evident Point Software Corp.</a>.</p>

<p>This project has <a href="http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/Readium-Web-Components/about/history-and-goals.html">evolved</a> from the <a href="http://readium.org">Readium</a> project. Readium was developed by <a href="https://github.com/matthewrobertson">Matthew Robertson</a> and <a href="http://github.com/justinHume">Justin Hume</a> at Evident Point Software under contract from the IDPF, with major contributions from <a href="http://www.benetech.org/literacy/bookshare.shtml">Benetech</a>, the <a href="http://www.daisy.org/home">DAISY Consortium</a> and <a href="https://github.com/readium/readium/contributors">others</a>.</p>

<h3>Start building and developing!</h3>

<p>Readium.js is currently in Beta, but we&#8217;re hoping to move things along quickly, stabilize the API, and add features. Feedback on any aspect of this site, or <a href="http://github.com/readium/Readium-Web-Components">Readium.js</a> is very welcome. If you&#8217;re interested in contributing, there is a long list of things to do and I&#8217;d be eager to walk you through it.</p>

<p>You can get in contact with me through the Readium.js <a href="https://github.com/readium/Readium-Web-Components/issues">issue tracker</a>, by email at justinh@evidentpoint.com, or through <a href="http://github.com/justinHume">Github</a>.</p>

<p>Otherwise, take a look around the site, and give Readium.js a try!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readium.js development]]></title>
    <link href="http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/blog/2013/05/28/readium-js-development/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-28T13:48:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/blog/2013/05/28/readium-js-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post discusses Readium.js development priorities up to now, as well as how you can get involved with the project.</p>

<h2>Motivation</h2>

<p>Readium.js is designed as a set of modular javascript components <!--more-->that can be used <a href="http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/Readium-Web-Components/get-started/download.html#simple-download">together</a> to embed EPUB publications in a web application, or <a href="http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/Readium-Web-Components/get-started/download.html#readium-js-download">independently</a> to build custom web applications with EPUB support.</p>

<h4>Fix things that are painful</h4>

<p>When a developer is looking for projects, it&#8217;s not uncommon to hear the suggestion that they work on a pain point. At <a href="http://evidentpoint.com">Evident Point</a>, I&#8217;ve been involved in building a number of web-based EPUB 3 readers. The original <a href="http://github.com/readium/readium">Readium</a> project often served as a template for these efforts.</p>

<p>While the original Readium provided a good demonstration of an EPUB 3 reader, I (and others, I believe) found it quite painful as developers to adapt the source to projects that were new, custom, or had more stringent requirements for performance, features etc.</p>

<p>By designing the Readium.js library it was my hope that Readium.js could, in typically-modern-web-javascript fashion, make it painless for developers to build a whole variety of web-based EPUB applications.</p>

<h4>Keep improving</h4>

<p>It&#8217;s also my hope that from here we can build a community around Readium.js to get the <a href="http://readium.github.io/Readium-Web-Components/Readium-Web-Components/get-started/api.html">API</a> right, build in additional features and improve digital publishing on the web.</p>

<p>The original Readium project was successful due to the <a href="https://github.com/readium/readium/issues">involvement</a> of a <a href="https://github.com/readium/readium/contributors">community</a>. Much of Readium.js is built on the contributions of this community - either code, wisdom, or lessons learned. I hope this can continue.</p>

<h2>Development Priorities</h2>

<p>During the development of Readium.js, I prioritized the things engineers like: The API design, a reasonable standard of engineering and solid documentation.</p>

<p>I felt it was important to get to a point where community members could reason about the design of the library and API, test the library, and get involved with the source code. I think getting the library &#8216;right&#8217; will depend on early feeback and iteration.</p>

<h4>Someone get the polish&#8230;</h4>

<p>As a result of this priority, some EPUB 3 feature support was lost in the design and refactoring. Getting these features back is in some cases just a matter of &#8220;turning&#8221; them back on. In some cases, it&#8217;ll be a bit more work. However, I think Readium.js will be back up to feature-completeness pretty quickly.</p>

<h2>How you can help</h2>

<p>I think Readium.js has some decent abstractions, encapsulation and documentation (in addition to some&#8230; rough naming), so the <a href="http://github.com/readium/Readium-Web-Components">code base</a> should be fairly accessible for contributors. I&#8217;ll also be able to help point you to where and how you can tackle certain things. Feedback and <a href="http://github.com/readium/Readium-Web-Components/issues">issue reports</a> are also very welcome.</p>

<p>If you know of something you&#8217;d like to contribute, feel free to get in touch (justinh@evidentpoint.com). If you&#8217;re looking for something (small or large) to contribute, you can choose from a list of things that need doing.</p>

<p>I hope you get involved.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
